Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
[Footprints of Change]
[آثار التغيير]
[Episode 1]
[الحلقة 1]
Ye Xining.
يي شينينغ.
[Interrogation Room 1]
[غرفة الاستجواب 1]
Shang Yunfei and his fiancée Huang Yahui are missing.
Shang Yunfei وخطيبته Huang Yahui مفقودان.
They're suspected of embezzling
يشتبه في أنهم اختلسوا
[Strict Law Enforcement]
[إنفاذ القانون الصارم]
more than 350,000 yuan.
أكثر من 350 ألف يوان.
We're currently looking for them.
نحن نبحث عنهم حاليا.
We'd like you to cooperate with our investigation.
نحن نود منك التعاون مع تحقيقنا.
That can't be.
هذا لا يمكن أن يكون.
What's your relationship
ما هي علاقتك
with Huang Yahui?
مع هوانغ ياهوي؟
We're colleagues.
نحن زملاء.
Huang Yahui was a cashier at your unit.
كان هوانغ ياهوي أمين صندوق في وحدتك.
Every one of these transfers bears your signature.
كل واحدة من هذه التحويلات تحمل توقيعك.
Do you know
هل تعلم
where the money went?
أين ذهبت الأموال؟
I signed them,
لقد وقعت عليهم
but I didn't approve the project.
ولكنني لم أوافق على المشروع.
I was just doing my job,
كنت فقط أقوم بعملي،
and I had no idea she was embezzling.
ولم يكن لدي أي فكرة أنها كانت تختلس.
Huang Yahui took out a personal loan,
حصل هوانغ ياهوي على قرض شخصي،
and you were her guarantor,
وكنت ضامنها
is that correct?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Since you were only colleagues,
وبما أنكم كنتم مجرد زملاء،
why did you agree to guarantee her loan?
لماذا وافقت على ضمان قرضها؟
We had worked together for 3 years
لقد عملنا معًا لمدة 3 سنوات
and we got along well.
وتوافقنا بشكل جيد.
Regarding Huang Yahui's case,
وفيما يتعلق بقضية هوانغ ياهوي،
I advise you to voluntarily disclose all relevant information.
أنصحك بالكشف طواعية عن جميع المعلومات ذات الصلة.
If you hide anything
إذا قمت بإخفاء أي شيء
and are subsequently classified as an accomplice,
ويتم تصنيفهم لاحقًا كشركاء،
you'll face severe legal repercussions.
سوف تواجه عواقب قانونية وخيمة.
Ye Xining,
يي شينينغ،
someone from your unit is here.
هناك شخص من وحدتك هنا.
You may go now.
يمكنك الذهاب الآن.
Director.
مخرج.
I'm so sorry.
أنا آسف جدا.
I never thought something like this would happen.
لم أكن أتوقع أبدًا أن يحدث شيء مثل هذا.
Go back to your dorm and rest for now.
ارجع إلى مسكنك واسترح الآن.
I'll wash up, get changed
سأغتسل وأغير ملابسي
and head to the bureau later.
والتوجه إلى المكتب لاحقًا.
I'll see you there.
سوف أراك هناك.
You should take a few days off to rest.
ينبغي عليك أن تأخذ بضعة أيام إجازة للراحة.
I... I don't need to rest.
أنا...لا أحتاج إلى الراحة.
This is a critical time for my promotion review.
هذا وقت حاسم لمراجعة ترقيتي.
I absolutely can't fall behind on work.
لا أستطيع التأخر عن العمل مطلقًا.
There's no need to rush back for work.
ليست هناك حاجة للعودة إلى العمل على عجل.
Just take a few days off.
فقط خذ بضعة أيام إجازة.
Director,
مخرج،
what do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Given what happened to Huang Yahui,
ونظرا لما حدث لهوانج ياهوي،
the bureau is holding an emergency meeting right now.
يعقد المكتب اجتماعا طارئا الآن.
I'm afraid that the situation doesn't look good for you.
أخشى أن الوضع لا يبدو جيدا بالنسبة لك.
You've been at the bureau for 3 years now.
لقد كنت في المكتب لمدة 3 سنوات الآن.
Do you really think the bureau
هل تعتقد حقا أن المكتب
will just let it go after Huang Yahui
سأترك الأمر بعد هوانغ ياهوي
made such a huge mess and ran off?
لقد أحدثت مثل هذه الفوضى الكبيرة وهربت؟
Ye,
نعم،
your promotion is off the table,
ترقيتك غير واردة
and you'll probably be held accountable.
ومن المرجح أن تتحمل المسؤولية.
Huang Yahui is the biggest embezzler
هوانغ ياهوي هو أكبر مختلس
our bureau has ever had.
لم يكن لمكتبنا مثل هذا من قبل.
Besides, the bureau believes
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، يعتقد المكتب
her embezzlement was enabled
لقد تم تمكين اختلاسها
by certain officials' dereliction of duty.
بسبب تقصير بعض المسؤولين في أداء واجباتهم.
Do you know what the crime of dereliction of duty is?
هل تعلم ما هي جريمة التقصير في أداء الواجب؟
The country has zero tolerance for it.
البلاد لا تتسامح مطلقا مع هذا الأمر.
As the police said,
كما قالت الشرطة،
if they find anything on you,
إذا وجدوا أي شيء عليك،
you could go to jail, too.
يمكنك الذهاب إلى السجن أيضًا.
Liu, why are you in such a hurry?
ليو، لماذا أنت في عجلة من أمرك؟
Ye Xining has collapsed! Go get help!
لقد انهار يي شينينج! اطلب المساعدة!
Okay, okay! I'll go help.
حسنًا، حسنًا! سأذهب للمساعدة.
Grandma.
الجدة.
Ning, you're awake.
نينج، أنت مستيقظ.
Just lie down.
فقط استلقي.
Are you thirsty?
هل انت عطشان؟
No, Grandma.
لا يا جدتي.
I know everything that's happened to you.
أنا أعلم كل ما حدث لك.
I want to tell you a story
أريد أن أخبرك قصة
about my aunt.
عن خالتي.
Maybe it will help you
ربما يساعدك
after you hear it.
بعد أن تسمعه.
I remember it was a hot summer in Shanghai.
أتذكر أنه كان صيفًا حارًا في شنغهاي.
My grandfather never got to see the person
لم يتمكن جدي من رؤية هذا الشخص أبدًا
he was waiting for before he passed.
كان ينتظر قبل أن يمر.
[1936, Shanghai]
[1936، شنغهاي]
I knew who he was waiting for.
لقد عرفت من كان ينتظره.
It was my aunt, who was studying in Germany at the time.
وكانت عمتي، التي كانت تدرس في ألمانيا في ذلك الوقت.
Becoming a doctor
أن تصبح طبيبًا
was my father's and my shared dream.
كان حلمي المشترك مع والدي.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
my father hid his illness and our family's struggles
لقد أخفى والدي مرضه ومعاناة عائلتنا
so I could focus on my studies abroad.
حتى أتمكن من التركيز على دراستي في الخارج.
I never expected
لم اتوقع ابدا
everything to happen so suddenly.
كل شيء يحدث فجأة.
May I ask your name, miss?
هل يمكنني أن أسألك عن اسمك يا آنسة؟
My surname is Lin.
لقبي هو لين.
You're beautiful.
أنت جميلة.
Do you have a ride?
هل لديك رحلة؟
Yes, I do.
نعم أفعل.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Nice glasses.
نظارات جميلة.
They're yours now.
إنهم لك الآن.
I bought them in the U.K.
لقد اشتريتهم في المملكة المتحدة
You didn't bring me any gifts for my homecoming?
لم تحضر لي أي هدايا بمناسبة عودتي إلى المنزل؟
Let's go home.
دعنا نذهب إلى المنزل.
[Exit]
[مخرج]
There she is.
ها هي ذا.
Auntie.
عمة.
You're finally back.
لقد عدت أخيرا.
Miss,
يفتقد،
what's in these suitcases?
ماذا يوجد في هذه الحقائب؟
Why are they so heavy?
لماذا هم ثقيلون جداً؟
It's all medical equipment I brought back from Germany.
إنها كلها معدات طبية أحضرتها من ألمانيا.
You two take one.
أنتما الإثنان تأخذان واحدة.
I'll carry this one myself.
سأحمل هذا بنفسي.
The waves were too rough on the way back,
كانت الأمواج شديدة للغاية في طريق العودة،
so it took a few extra days.
لذلك استغرق الأمر بضعة أيام إضافية.
How are things with your grandpa?
كيف هي الأمور مع جدك؟
My dad took care of everything.
والدي اهتم بكل شيء.
How's the rest of the family?
كيف حال بقية العائلة؟
They're fine.
إنهم بخير.
Siyun.
صهيون.
Long time no see.
وقت طويل لا رؤية.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
You've grown up,
لقد كبرت
and you're even more beautiful.
وأنت أكثر جمالا.
Do you remember this bike?
هل تتذكر هذه الدراجة؟
I used to take you out on it when you were little.
كنت آخذك معي عندما كنت صغيراً.
I specially rode it here just to pick you up.
لقد ركبتها خصيصًا هنا فقط لالتقاطك.
Come on, I'll take you home.
تعال، سأوصلك إلى المنزل.
I do remember.
انا أتذكر.
But...
لكن...
I have Yi and Xiu with me.
معي يي و شيو.
We can take a rickshaw back.
يمكننا أن نأخذ عربة الريكشا للعودة.
Thank you,
شكرًا لك،
Shen Yiqun.
شين يكوين.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
She's really grown up.
لقد كبرت حقا.
Dad.
أب.
I'm home.
أنا الوطن.
Siyun,
صهيون،
have you contacted the Qiao family?
هل تواصلت مع عائلة تشياو؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
I'll go with you tomorrow to visit the Qiao family.
سأذهب معك غدًا لزيارة عائلة تشياو.
There's no need to rush.
ليست هناك حاجة للتسرع.
How can you say that?
كيف يمكنك أن تقول ذلك؟
Your marriage arrangement with the Qiao family
ترتيبات زواجك مع عائلة تشياو
has been postponed again and again because of your studies.
لقد تم تأجيلها مرارا وتكرارا بسبب دراستك.
Now that Dad's gone,
الآن بعد أن رحل أبي،
what if the Qiao family changed their mind
ماذا لو غيرت عائلة تشياو رأيها؟
and canceled the engagement?
وألغيت الخطوبة؟
What would we do then?
ماذا سنفعل حينها؟
Jinghan,
جينغان,
Dad just passed away.
لقد توفي والدي للتو.
Is this really the right time to talk about this?
هل هذا هو الوقت المناسب حقا للحديث عن هذا؟
Alright,
على ما يرام،
you're right.
أنت على حق.
Madam,
سيدتي،
there's a group of people in the yard.
هناك مجموعة من الناس في الفناء.
Who are they?
من هم؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
They seem to be from the Zeng family.
يبدو أنهم من عائلة زينج.
Well,
حسنًا،
I'll go check on your sister-in-law upstairs.
سأذهب للتحقق من أخت زوجتك في الطابق العلوي.
I'll go up and see how she's doing.
سأذهب وأرى كيف حالها.
Mrs. Lin.
السيدة لين.
Madam,
سيدتي،
I'm Mr. Zeng's lawyer,
أنا محامي السيد زينج،
Cheng Ao.
تشنغ آو.
I'm here to see Lin Jinghan about something.
أنا هنا لرؤية لين جينغهان بشأن شيء ما.
Why is everyone so quiet?
لماذا الجميع هادئون هكذا؟
Who's actually in charge here?
من هو المسؤول هنا فعليا؟
Here's the thing.
هذا هو الشيء.
Lin Jinghan owes Mr. Zeng money,
لين جينغان مدين للسيد زينج بالمال،
and it's been overdue for 6 months.
وقد تأخر ذلك لمدة 6 أشهر.
He mortgaged your house as collateral.
لقد رهن منزلك كضمان.
If he doesn't repay the debt,
إذا لم يسدد الدين،
we'll have to seize your property.
سوف يتوجب علينا الاستيلاء على ممتلكاتك.
We didn't mean to disturb you today.
لم نقصد إزعاجك اليوم.
We just need to see Lin Jinghan.
نحن بحاجة فقط لرؤية لين جينغهان.
How much does Lin Jinghan owe you?
كم يدين لك لين جينغهان؟
Lin Jinghan isn't here.
لين جينغهان ليس هنا.
He hasn't been around for a long time.
لم يكن موجودا منذ فترة طويلة.
Search.
يبحث.
Have we...
هل لدينا...
met before?
التقيت من قبل؟
I don't know you.
أنا لا أعرفك.
You're really beautiful.
أنت جميلة حقا.
Yi,
يفعل،
go upstairs and check on your mom.
اصعد إلى الطابق العلوي واطمئن على والدتك.
Call me if she shows any symptoms.
اتصل بي إذا ظهرت عليها أي أعراض.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll come right up.
سوف آتي في الحال.
How much does Jinghan owe them?
كم يدين لهم جينغان؟
Quite a lot, I think.
الكثير جدًا، على ما أعتقد.
It must be a significant amount.
لا بد أن تكون كمية كبيرة.
How much exactly?
كم بالضبط؟
A debt is a debt—we can just repay it.
الدين هو الدين، ونحن قادرون على سداده.
Where would we get the money to pay it back?
من أين نحصل على المال لسدادها؟
During the years your father was ill,
خلال السنوات التي كان فيها والدك مريضًا،
everyone avoided us.
الجميع تجنبونا.
Now that your father is gone,
الآن وقد رحل والدك،
who would even pay attention to us?
من يهتم بنا؟
Even the banks are snobs,
حتى البنوك متغطرسة،
and they won't grant us a loan.
ولن يمنحونا قرضًا.
It hurts.
إنه يؤلمني.
Xiu,
شيو،
take my mom upstairs too.
خذ أمي إلى الطابق العلوي أيضًا.
Ao,
الى،
no sign of Lin Jinghan on the first floor.
لا يوجد أي أثر للين جينغان في الطابق الأول.
Then search the second floor.
ثم ابحث في الطابق الثاني.
When you find Lin Jinghan, break one of his legs first.
عندما تجد لين جينغهان، اكسر إحدى ساقيه أولاً.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
It hurts.
إنه يؤلمني.
Ao,
الى،
we couldn't find him.
لم نتمكن من العثور عليه.
This is my bedroom.
هذه غرفتي.
You can't go in!
لا يمكنك الدخول!
My sister-in-law is inside.
أخت زوجي في الداخل.
She's about to give birth.
إنها على وشك الولادة.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Lin Jinghan
لين جينغان
must come with us.
يجب أن يأتي معنا.
Try going in if you dare!
حاول الدخول إذا كنت تجرؤ!
Is she going to cut you?
هل ستقطعك؟
It seems like it.
يبدو الأمر كذلك.
She wouldn't dare.
انها لن تجرؤ.
He won't hurt you either.
ولن يؤذيك أيضًا.
I know this man.
انا اعرف هذا الرجل.
He always keeps his word and handles things professionally.
إنه دائمًا يفي بكلمته ويتعامل مع الأمور باحترافية.
Here, give me this cleaver.
تفضل، أعطني هذا الساطور.
Be good.
كن جيدا.
That was scary.
كان ذلك مخيفا.
She actually did it!
لقد فعلتها فعلا!
Do you want me to shoot a bullet through your dimple?
هل تريد مني أن أطلق رصاصة على غمازتك؟
Are you crazy?
هل انت مجنون؟
Why are you bullying a girl?
لماذا تتنمر على فتاة؟
She cut me.
لقد قطعتني.
Didn't you bring that on yourself?
ألم تجلب ذلك على نفسك؟
Auntie, my mom is in labor!
عمة أمي في حالة المخاض!
I'll give you 30 days.
سأعطيك 30 يومًا.
Tell Lin Jinghan.
أخبر لين جينغان.
Get the money ready within 30 days.
احصل على الأموال جاهزة خلال 30 يومًا.
This is the final deadline.
هذا هو الموعد النهائي.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Boss says we're leaving.
يقول الرئيس أننا سنغادر.
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Are you leaving or not?
هل ستغادر أم لا؟
Let's go!
دعنا نذهب!
I need a quick bandage.
أحتاج إلى ضمادة سريعة.
Is it a boy or a girl?
هل هو ولد أم بنت؟
Does it matter?
هل يهم؟
No, it doesn't.
لا، لا يحدث ذلك.
Siyun,
صهيون،
with all this chaos at home today,
مع كل هذه الفوضى في المنزل اليوم،
thank goodness you're here to help deliver the baby.
الحمد لله أنك هنا للمساعدة في ولادة الطفل.
Great.
عظيم.
It's a boy.
إنه ولد.
Our Lin family finally has an heir.
عائلة لين لدينا أخيرا وريث.
He's so beautiful.
إنه جميل جداً.
He looks just like your dad
إنه يشبه والدك تمامًا
when he was just born.
عندما ولد للتو.
I think he looks more like my mom.
أعتقد أنه يشبه أمي أكثر.
What's wrong with your eyes?
ما الخطأ في عينيك؟
Sister-in-law.
أخت الزوج أو اخت الزوجة.
Yi,
يفعل،
get your mother a glass of water.
أحضر لوالدتك كوبًا من الماء.
Okay.
تمام.
How are you feeling?
كيف تشعر؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Where's Lin Jinghan?
أين لين جينغان؟
I... I'm here.
انا...انا هنا.
Down here.
هنا في الأسفل.
Here.
هنا.
Siyun,
صهيون،
are they all gone?
هل ذهبوا جميعا؟
How did you make them leave?
كيف جعلتهم يرحلون؟
Tell me about it.
أخبرني عن ذلك.
How did you get in there?
كيف دخلت إلى هناك؟
Mom,
أم،
Xiu and Yi,
شيو ويي،
they lifted the bedboard for me.
لقد رفعوا لوح السرير من أجلي.
In that critical moment,
في تلك اللحظة الحرجة،
I crawled in here.
لقد زحفت إلى هنا.
Why didn't you tell me you owed so much money?
لماذا لم تخبرني أنك مدين بهذا القدر من المال؟
Well, you just got back,
حسنًا، لقد عدت للتو،
I needed time to tell you.
كنت بحاجة إلى الوقت لأخبرك.
I just heard
لقد سمعت للتو
that you're in charge of the family now.
أنك المسؤول عن العائلة الآن.
Do you have a good plan to help me repay the debt?
هل لديك خطة جيدة لمساعدتي في سداد الدين؟
You owe the money.
أنت مدين بالمال.
Yes, right.
نعم صحيح.
I didn't mean anything else.
لم أقصد شيئا آخر.
I know I owe the money.
أعلم أنني مدين بالمال.
But aren't you marrying into the Qiao family?
ولكن هل ستتزوج من عائلة تشياو؟
The Qiao family owns a huge bank.
تملك عائلة تشياو بنكًا ضخمًا.
Surely you can help me.
بالتأكيد يمكنك مساعدتي.
Please help me.
من فضلك ساعدني.
Tell me if you have any good ideas.
أخبرني إذا كان لديك أي أفكار جيدة.
You owe the money,
أنت مدين بالمال
so you pay it back yourself.
لذلك عليك أن تسددها بنفسك.
What's wrong with her?
ماذا بها؟
Mom,
أم،
come here,
تعال الى هنا،
come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Help me lift
ساعدني على الرفع
this bed board
لوح السرير هذا
so I can get out.
حتى أتمكن من الخروج.
I'm suffocating down here.
أنا أختنق هنا.
Jinghan,
جينغان,
take a look at your son!
أنظر إلى ابنك!
He looks so much like you.
إنه يشبهك كثيرًا.
I see him—he does look like me.
أنا أراه، إنه يشبهني.
Lift the bed board
ارفع لوح السرير
and get me out—I can barely breathe!
وأخرجوني-بالكاد أستطيع التنفس!
This child is really beautiful.
هذا الطفل جميل حقا.
Yes, yes, he is.
نعم، نعم، هو كذلك.
But I'm stuck in here,
ولكنني عالق هنا،
-and I can't even see him. -He looks just like you.
-ولا أستطيع حتى رؤيته. -إنه يشبهك تمامًا.
Hey, I just realized that
مهلا، لقد أدركت للتو أن
you've forgotten your own son since you got a grandson.
لقد نسيت ابنك منذ أن أصبح لديك حفيد.
How could you do this to me?
كيف يمكنك أن تفعل هذا بي؟
I know I'm in debt, but you can't treat me like this!
أعرف أنني مدين، لكن لا يمكنك معاملتي بهذه الطريقة!
Look at those eyes.
أنظر إلى تلك العيون.
They're exactly like yours.
إنهم مثلك تمامًا.
We came all this way for nothing today.
لقد جئنا كل هذه المسافة من أجل لا شيء اليوم.
We didn't collect the debt.
لم نجمع الدين
How are you going to explain this to my dad when you get back?
كيف ستشرح هذا الأمر لأبي عندما تعود؟
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
I'll talk to him.
سأتحدث معه.
You're still so aggressive.
مازلت عدوانيًا جدًا.
You always act recklessly,
أنت تتصرف دائمًا بتهور،
doing whatever you want without thinking.
افعل ما تريد دون تفكير.
Since when do you hit women?
منذ متى تضرب النساء؟
I've been different from others since I was a kid.
لقد كنت مختلفًا عن الآخرين منذ أن كنت طفلاً.
Do you know about a hormone
هل تعرف عن هرمون
called adrenaline?
ما يسمى الأدرينالين؟
My adrenaline levels
مستويات الأدرينالين لدي
are higher than average,
أعلى من المتوسط،
so I'm prone to high blood pressure.
لذلك أنا عرضة لارتفاع ضغط الدم.
Is high blood pressure contagious?
هل ارتفاع ضغط الدم معدٍ؟
Your friend seems short-tempered too.
يبدو أن صديقك سريع الغضب أيضًا.
You're Jin, right?
أنت جين، أليس كذلك؟
How's your blood pressure?
كيف ضغط دمك؟
It's normal.
إنه أمر طبيعي.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
From now on, when we're out, speak when you should,
من الآن فصاعدًا، عندما نخرج، تحدث عندما يجب عليك ذلك،
and keep quiet
و ابقى هادئا
when you shouldn't.
عندما لا ينبغي لك ذلك.
Jin,
إحساس،
make a toast to Ao.
اصنع نخبًا لـ Ao.
Ao, here's to you.
أوه، هنا لك.
Cheers, Cheng.
شكرا، تشنغ.
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Say that again, I dare you.
قل ذلك مرة أخرى، أتحداك.
Stop, stop.
توقف، توقف.
I just got back.
لقد عدت للتو.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I'll dance for you guys.
سأرقص لكم يا رفاق.
Follow me.
اتبعني.
Have some tea.
تناول بعض الشاي.
Shijun,
شيجون،
long time no see.
وقت طويل لا رؤية.
You've studied abroad too.
لقد درست في الخارج أيضاً.
Do you approve of arranged marriages?
هل توافق على الزواج المدبر؟
Do you think we could be happy
هل تعتقد أننا يمكن أن نكون سعداء؟
if we got married?
إذا تزوجنا؟
When I was in middle school, I promised Siyun
عندما كنت في المدرسة المتوسطة، وعدت سيون
that I would make her
أنني سأجعلها
the happiest bride in Shanghai.
أسعد عروس في شنغهاي.
Everyone laughed at me back then,
لقد ضحك الجميع علي في ذلك الوقت،
but I meant it.
ولكنني قصدت ذلك.
A big reason I went to study abroad later
السبب الرئيسي الذي دفعني للدراسة في الخارج لاحقًا
was actually because of Siyun.
كان في الواقع بسبب سيون.
I thought we could go together
اعتقدت أننا يمكن أن نذهب معا
and look out for each other.
والعناية ببعضنا البعض.
But I never expected
ولكنني لم أتوقع أبدا
she would go to Germany while I went to America.
كانت ستذهب إلى ألمانيا بينما كنت سأذهب إلى أمريكا.
A girl alone in a foreign country
فتاة وحيدة في بلد أجنبي
must have suffered much more than I did.
لا بد وأنني عانيت أكثر مما عانيت.
I don't approve of arranged marriages.
أنا لا أوافق على الزواج المدبر.
But Siyun,
ولكن صهيون،
could you give me, Qiao Shijun, a chance?
هل يمكن أن تعطيني، تشياو شيجون، فرصة؟
Let's get to know each other again.
دعونا نتعرف على بعضنا البعض مرة أخرى.
Yes, of course.
نعم بالطبع.
Well said.
حسنا قيل.
Marriage is a big deal, and it should be decided by parents.
الزواج أمر كبير، ويجب أن يقرره الأهل.
Do you remember when you two were kids, building blocks
هل تتذكرون عندما كنتم طفلين، بناء المكعبات؟
and holding hands?
ومسك اليدين؟
Now that you've grown up,
الآن بعد أن كبرت،
you even have the same long eyes
حتى أن لديك نفس العيون الطويلة
and oval face.
ووجه بيضاوي.
Chin up.
إرفع رأسك.
Look at that tall nose bridge.
أنظر إلى جسر الأنف الطويل.
You two really look alike.
أنتم الاثنان متشابهان حقا.
Isn't that what they call the couples' resemblance?
أليس هذا ما يسمونه تشابه الزوجين؟
Uncle Qiao.
العم تشياو.
Couples who look alike
الأزواج المتشابهون
usually have beautiful children.
عادة ما يكون لديهم أطفال جميلين.
Whether the child looks like Siyun
هل يبدو الطفل مثل سيون؟
or Shijun,
أو شيجون،
they're bound to be good-looking.
من المؤكد أنهم سيكونون حسن المظهر.
Did Mr. Qiao ask for your opinion?
هل طلب السيد تشياو رأيك؟
Uncle Qiao,
العم تشياو
I think we should
أعتقد أننا يجب أن
arrange their marriage
ترتيب زواجهم
in the next day or two.
في اليوم التالي أو اليومين التاليين.
We should invite all the influential people
ينبغي علينا دعوة جميع الأشخاص المؤثرين
in Shanghai.
في شنغهاي.
The next day or two?
اليوم التالي أو اليومين التاليين؟
Tomorrow it is, then.
غدا إذن.
Isn't that too rushed?
أليس هذا متسرعًا جدًا؟
Shijun,
شيجون،
take some time
خذ بعض الوقت
to spend with Siyun.
لقضاء الوقت مع سيون.
You haven't seen each other in years, right?
لم ترى بعضكما البعض منذ سنوات، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Right, right.
يمينًا، يمينًا.
Spend more time together.
اقضوا المزيد من الوقت معًا.
Go see a movie,
اذهب لرؤية فيلم
have dinner and chat.
تناول العشاء والدردشة.
Get reacquainted
التعرف مجددًا
and enjoy some sweet moments.
واستمتع ببعض اللحظات الجميلة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
We won't take up any more of your time today.
لن نشغل وقتك أكثر اليوم.
Well... Shijun...
حسنا .. شيجون ..
is quite tall.
طويل جدًا.
Well, Mr. Qiao, Shijun,
حسنًا، سيد تشياو، شيجون،
take care.
يعتني.
I'll see you out.
سأراك في الخارج.
Siyun,
صهيون،
what would you like to eat?
ماذا تحب أن تأكل؟
I'll cook for you myself today.
سأطبخ لك بنفسي اليوم.
Just looking at you, I'm already full.
بمجرد النظر إليك، أشعر أنني ممتلئ بالفعل.
[Ju De Hall Restaurant]
[مطعم جو دي هول]
Siyun.
صهيون.
I'm not late, am I?
أنا لست متأخرًا، أليس كذلك؟
No.
لا.
I've already ordered for you.
لقد طلبت لك بالفعل.
They're all your favorites.
إنهم كلهم ​​المفضلين لديك.
How did you know these are my favorite dishes?
كيف عرفت أن هذه هي أطباقي المفضلة؟
I wrote them down in a notebook when we were little.
لقد كتبتها في دفتر ملاحظات عندما كنا صغارًا.
You... you wrote them down?
أنت... هل كتبتهم؟
I also remember
انا اتذكر ايضا
that before you went abroad, you said
أنك قبل أن تذهب إلى الخارج قلت
you wanted to open a maternity hospital when you returned.
أردت أن تفتح مستشفى للولادة عند عودتك.
I can't believe you still remember that.
لا أستطيع أن أصدق أنك لا تزال تتذكر ذلك.
Of course I do.
بالطبع أفعل.
And I think
وأنا أعتقد
opening a maternity hospital has great potential.
إن افتتاح مستشفى للولادة له إمكانيات كبيرة.
There's a real need for it here in our country.
هناك حاجة حقيقية لذلك هنا في بلدنا.
It's a great choice.
إنه اختيار رائع.
Shijun,
شيجون،
thank you for supporting me.
شكرا لدعمك لي.
Your business is my business.
عملك هو عملي.
How could I not support you?
كيف لا أستطيع أن أدعمك؟
Hurry and eat before the food gets cold.
اسرع وتناول الطعام قبل أن يبرد.
Cold food is bad for your stomach.
الطعام البارد مضر للمعدة.
[Light Theater]
[مسرح الضوء]
Xiu,
شيو،
how was the movie? Not bad, right?
كيف كان الفيلم؟ ليس سيئًا، أليس كذلك؟
It was good.
لقد كان جيدا.
You liked it?
هل اعجبك ذلك؟
I'll take you to movies every day from now on.
سأأخذك إلى السينما كل يوم من الآن فصاعدا.
You two can leave now.
يمكنكم المغادرة الآن.
Xiu,
شيو،
I'll take you somewhere nice to eat.
سأأخذك إلى مكان لطيف لتناول الطعام.
I... I don't want to eat.
أنا...لا أريد أن آكل.
It's getting late.
لقد أصبح الوقت متأخرًا.
I should head back.
ينبغي لي أن أعود.
Well, I mean,
حسنا، أعني،
it's just a quick bite. It won't take long.
إنها مجرد لقمة سريعة، ولن تستغرق وقتًا طويلاً.
Are you blind or something?
هل أنت أعمى أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Xiu, are you scared of me?
شيو هل أنت خائفة مني؟
We're from the same hometown.
نحن من نفس المدينة.
I've liked you for years.
لقد أحببتك لسنوات.
Can't you just give me a chance?
هل يمكنك أن تعطيني فرصة؟
If you don't want to eat, we won't.
إذا كنت لا تريد أن تأكل، فلن نفعل.
I'll take you home.
سأوصلك إلى المنزل.
I... I can take a rickshaw back myself.
أنا... أنا قادر على أخذ عربة الريكشا بنفسي.
That won't do.
هذا لن يفعل.
I'll take you back
سأعيدك
the way I brought you here.
الطريقة التي أحضرتك بها إلى هنا.
I promise,
أعدك،
I have no bad intentions.
ليس لدي أي نوايا سيئة.
Just trust me this once, okay?
فقط ثق بي هذه المرة، حسنًا؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Let's go get something to eat.
دعنا نذهب للحصول على شيء للأكل.
I only agreed to watch a movie with you,
لقد وافقت فقط على مشاهدة فيلم معك،
not have dinner.
لا يوجد عشاء.
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
I'm hungry. Can't you just eat with me?
أنا جائع. ألا يمكنكِ تناول الطعام معي؟
Is that too much to ask?
هل هذا كثير جدًا؟
You promised
لقد وعدت
you'd take me home after the movie.
ستأخذني إلى المنزل بعد الفيلم.
I'll ask you one more time.
سأسألك مرة أخرى.
Are you eating or not?
هل تأكل أم لا؟
No.
لا.
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Stop the car!
أوقف السيارة!
Why couldn't you just let me kiss you and get it over with?
لماذا لا تسمح لي بتقبيلك وإنهاء الأمر؟
Now look at what happened.
الآن انظر ماذا حدث.
You hit your head wide open.
لقد ضربت رأسك مفتوحا على مصراعيه.
Have a seat.
خذ مقعدا.
There're so many girls in Shanghai to have fun with.
هناك العديد من الفتيات في شنغهاي لقضاء وقت ممتع معهن.
Don't tell me you actually loved that maid.
لا تخبرني أنك أحببت تلك الخادمة فعلاً.
I did have feelings for her,
لقد كانت لدي مشاعر تجاهها،
but I never thought she'd actually die.
ولكنني لم أتوقع أبدًا أنها ستموت فعليًا.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Take it easy.
خذها ببساطة.
If the sky falls,
إذا سقطت السماء
my dad will hold it up.
والدي سوف يحملها.
If it falls again, I'll hold it up.
إذا سقط مرة أخرى، سأحمله.
I'll help you with this.
سأساعدك في هذا.
Don't you need to drive?
هل لا تحتاج إلى القيادة؟
No. I don't have a car.
لا، ليس لدي سيارة.
Whose car is it, then?
من هي السيارة إذن؟
It's your car.
إنها سيارتك.
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Hello, Cheng Ao.
مرحباً، تشنغ آو.
Who's this?
من هذا؟
Guess who I am.
أخمن من أنا.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
That maid from the Lin family jumped out of my car,
قفزت تلك الخادمة من عائلة لين من سيارتي،
hit her head on the curb,
ضربت رأسها على الرصيف،
and she's dead.
وهي ميتة.
I need you to check it out for me.
أريد منك التحقق من ذلك بالنسبة لي.
Her body's at Zhongde Hospital.
جثتها موجودة في مستشفى تشونجدي.
Auntie...
عمة...
Xiu is dead.
شيو مات.
We'll never see her again.
لن نراها مرة أخرى.
Miss Lin,
الآنسة لين،
I'm Zeng Dalun's lawyer.
أنا محامي زينج دالون.
I'm here to express
أنا هنا للتعبير
condolences to the victim's family.
تعازينا لأسرة الضحية.
If it's convenient for you now,
إذا كان ذلك مناسبًا لك الآن،
we can have a talk.
يمكننا أن نتحدث.
Any requests
أي طلبات
or compensation,
أو التعويض،
you can discuss them with me.
يمكنك مناقشتها معي.
I don't want any compensation.
لا أريد أي تعويض.
Please tell Zeng Dalun
من فضلك أخبر زينج دالون
that he will pay
انه سوف يدفع
for what he's done.
لما فعله.
[Memorial tablet of Lin Shuping]
[لوحة تذكارية للين شوبينغ]
Siyun,
صهيون،
you're back.
لقد عدت.
How did it go?
كيف كان الأمر؟
How was it?
كيف وجدته؟
Siyun,
صهيون،
has the wedding date been set?
هل تم تحديد موعد الزفاف؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Did you have a fight with Mr. Qiao?
هل تشاجرت مع السيد تشياو؟
How many times have I told you?
كم مرة قلت لك؟
Don't act like a spoiled young lady again.
لا تتصرفي مثل فتاة مدللة مرة أخرى.
How could you argue with Mr. Qiao?
كيف يمكنك الجدال مع السيد تشياو؟
Mr. Qiao's such a nice person.
السيد تشياو شخص لطيف للغاية.
He has such a calm temper.
إنه يتمتع بطبع هادئ.
It must be your fault, right?
لا بد أن يكون هذا خطؤك، أليس كذلك؟
Don't you guys care about Xiu at all?
ألا تهتمون بـ Xiu على الإطلاق؟
Who?
من؟
Xiu?
شيو؟
I mean, didn't you report it
أعني، ألم تبلغ عن ذلك؟
to the police station this morning?
إلى مركز الشرطة هذا الصباح؟
Leave Xiu's case to the police.
اترك قضية شيو للشرطة.
Focus on what matters,
ركز على ما يهم
like planning your own wedding, okay?
مثل التخطيط لحفل زفافك الخاص، حسنًا؟
Xiu was murdered.
لقد تم اغتيال شيو.
I can't get married now.
لا أستطيع الزواج الآن.
I understand,
أفهم،
Xiu was Nanny's daughter,
شيو كانت ابنة المربية،
and Nanny was alawys good to you when you were little,
وكانت المربية دائمًا جيدة معك عندما كنت صغيرًا،
right?
يمين؟
When you got sick, she'd stay up all night watching over you.
عندما كنت مريضًا، كانت تبقى مستيقظة طوال الليل لمراقبتك.
I get it.
أحصل عليه.
That child, Xiu, had a hard life.
لقد عاش ذلك الطفل، شيو، حياة صعبة.
But since she's gone,
ولكن منذ رحلت،
we should comfort her father.
ينبغي علينا أن نعزي والدها.
We'll cover the funeral expenses.
سوف نقوم بتغطية تكاليف الجنازة.
Would that be okay?
هل سيكون ذلك مقبولا؟
Siyun,
صهيون،
just focus on preparing for your wedding.
فقط ركز على الاستعداد لحفل زفافك.
As for Xiu's case,
أما بالنسبة لقضية شيو،
just leave it to Jinghan,
فقط اترك الأمر لجينغان،
okay?
تمام؟
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Siyun,
صهيون،
my father would like to invite you to our home for dinner tonight.
يريد والدي أن يدعوك إلى منزلنا لتناول العشاء الليلة.
Please prepare for it.
يرجى الاستعداد لذلك.
I'll have someone come pick you up later.
سأطلب من شخص ما أن يأتي ليلتقطك لاحقًا.
Shijun,
شيجون،
Xiu is dead.
شيو مات.
I need to take care of her funeral
أحتاج إلى الاهتمام بجنازتها
and the lawsuit.
والدعوى.
I won't be able to make it to dinner.
لن أتمكن من الذهاب إلى العشاء.
Who is Xiu?
من هو شيو؟
My nanny's daughter.
ابنة مربيتي.
Alright,
على ما يرام،
then you should take care of Xiu's matter first.
إذن عليك الاهتمام بأمر شيو أولاً.
Don't be too sad.
لا تحزن كثيرا
Take care of yourself and don't wear yourself out.
اعتني بنفسك ولا ترهق نفسك.
My condolences.
تعازيّ.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Was that my future brother-in-law on the phone?
هل كان هذا صهرى المستقبلي على الهاتف؟
Are you having dinner with him tonight?
هل تتناول العشاء معه الليلة؟
You should eat, drink,
يجب عليك أن تأكل وتشرب
and enjoy your time.
واستمتع بوقتك.
Why don't you go by yourself?
لماذا لا تذهب بنفسك؟
Is this Dr. Lin Siyun's residence?
هل هذا هو منزل الدكتور لين سيون؟
I'm Ling, a midwife from Zhongde Hospital.
أنا لينغ، قابلة من مستشفى تشونجدي.
The director asked me to inform you
لقد طلب مني المخرج أن أخبرك
that your job application has been approved.
أن طلب الوظيفة الخاص بك قد تمت الموافقة عليه.
You can come to the hospital next Monday to handle the paperwork.
يمكنك الحضور إلى المستشفى يوم الاثنين المقبل لإتمام الإجراءات الورقية.
Okay,
تمام،
I understand.
أفهم.
Was that Shijun on the phone again?
هل كان هذا شيجون على الهاتف مرة أخرى؟
Siyun, listen to me.
سييون، استمع لي.
Would I ever harm you?
هل سأؤذيك يوما ما؟
I'm your own brother.
أنا أخوك.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Tonight, you...
الليلة، أنت...
Tonight,
الليلة،
you must go to have dinner with him.
يجب عليك أن تذهب لتناول العشاء معه.
If you offend him,
إذا أسأت إليه،
it'll affect the wedding.
سيؤثر على حفل الزفاف.
Most importantly, it's about the Lin family's legacy.
والأهم من ذلك كله، يتعلق الأمر بإرث عائلة لين.
Do you hear me?
هل تسمعني؟
Mom,
أم،
I want to postpone the wedding.
أريد تأجيل الزفاف.
Why do you want to postpone it?
لماذا تريد تأجيله؟
Xiu was murdered.
لقد تم اغتيال شيو.
Yes, I'm also sad
نعم، أنا حزين أيضًا
that Xiu died.
أن شيو مات.
But at the end of the day, wasn't she just an outsider?
ولكن في نهاية المطاف، أليست مجرد دخيلة؟
Can't you tell what's more important?
ألا يمكنك أن تقول ما هو أكثر أهمية؟
If you keep messing around like this,
إذا واصلت العبث بهذه الطريقة،
the Lin family will be ruined by you sooner or later!
سوف يتم تدمير عائلة لين بسببك عاجلاً أم آجلاً!
Have you no shame?
هل ليس لديك خجل؟
Is it me ruining the family or you?
هل أنا من دمر العائلة أم أنت؟
Siyun,
صهيون،
just listen to your brother.
فقط استمع إلى أخيك.
Don't worry about Xiu's case for now.
لا تقلق بشأن قضية شيو في الوقت الراهن.
Let Jinghan handle it,
دع جينغان يتعامل مع الأمر،
okay?
تمام؟
All he wants is for the Qiao family to pay off his debts.
كل ما يريده هو أن تسدد عائلة تشياو ديونه.
How can he be so despicable?
كيف يمكن أن يكون حقيرًا إلى هذه الدرجة؟
Since you put it that way,
بما أنك وضعت الأمر بهذه الطريقة،
then we need to have a real talk
إذن نحن بحاجة إلى إجراء محادثة حقيقية
in front of our mom.
أمام أمنا.
You've had the finest food and drinks since childhood.
لقد تناولت أجود أنواع الطعام والمشروبات منذ الطفولة.
We never mistreated you, right?
نحن لم نعاملك بشكل سيء أبدًا، أليس كذلك؟
That's because of the Lin family.
وهذا بسبب عائلة لين.
Sending you abroad
إرسالك إلى الخارج
to study,
للدراسة
getting a foreign education,
الحصول على تعليم أجنبي،
having all that knowledge to show off...
امتلاك كل هذه المعرفة لإظهارها...
that's also because of the Lin family.
وهذا أيضًا بسبب عائلة لين.
People...
الناس...
shouldn't forget where they came from.
لا ينبغي أن ننسى من أين أتوا.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
The reputation earned by the Lin family's ancestors
السمعة التي اكتسبها أسلاف عائلة لين
and the upbringing they gave me
والتربية التي قدموها لي
mean I must repay them.
أعني أنني يجب أن أسدد لهم.
But I'm repaying the Lin family
ولكنني أسدد دين عائلة لين
and my parents.
ووالدي.
Why should I have to pay off the debts you owe?
لماذا يجب علي أن أسدد الديون المستحقة عليك؟
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
I was sent abroad on a government scholarship.
لقد تم إرسالي إلى الخارج بمنحة حكومية.
I worked to support myself in Germany for 4 years
عملت لدعم نفسي في ألمانيا لمدة 4 سنوات
and didn't spend a cent of the family's money.
ولم ينفق سنتًا واحدًا من أموال العائلة.
You've been in business for years.
لقد كنت في العمل لسنوات.
Have you earned anything?
هل كسبت شيئا؟
The Lin family served as officials for generations,
عملت عائلة لين كمسؤولين لأجيال،
and remained wealthy for over a century.
وظل ثريًا لأكثر من قرن من الزمان.
Now creditors are coming to our door to collect debts.
الآن يأتي الدائنون إلى بابنا لتحصيل الديون.
Our reputation is damaged,
سمعتنا تضررت،
and we can't even keep our residence.
ونحن لا نستطيع حتى الاحتفاظ بإقامتنا.
Whose fault is this, really?
من المسؤول عن هذا حقا؟
Who squandered the Lin family's fortune?
من بدد ثروة عائلة لين؟
Ao,
الى،
I'd like to report something to you.
أريد أن أبلغك بشيء ما.
Go ahead.
تفضل.
The day the Lin family's maid died,
في اليوم الذي توفيت فيه خادمة عائلة لين،
Young Master didn't go to the theater.
لم يذهب الشاب إلى المسرح.
That son of the Liu family
هذا ابن عائلة ليو
picked him up to go drinking.
أخذته ليذهب للشرب.
And he took you along as well?
وأخذك معه أيضًا؟
Yes, he did.
نعم لقد فعل.
Then who drove his car?
إذن من الذي قاد سيارته؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
Alright, I got it.
حسنا، لقد حصلت عليه.
Ao,
الى،
this is a big deal.
هذه مشكلة كبيرة.
Should we tell Master?
هل يجب علينا أن نخبر المعلم؟
With Dalun's personality,
مع شخصية دالون،
if he's determined to do this,
إذا كان مصمما على القيام بذلك،
telling Master won't help.
إخبار المعلم لن يساعد.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
Dalun...
لقد خرجوا...
is hard to deal with.
من الصعب التعامل معه.
So what should we do?
إذن ماذا يجب علينا أن نفعل؟
Don't worry. Let me think about it.
لا تقلق، دعني أفكر في الأمر.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
Do you have coffee here?
هل يوجد قهوة هنا؟
No.
لا.
Who would drink coffee this late at night?
من يشرب القهوة في هذا الوقت المتأخر من الليل؟
About Zeng Dalun's case...
حول قضية زينج دالون...
you're his defense lawyer, right?
أنت محامي الدفاع عنه، أليس كذلك؟
The eldest daughter of the Lin family came to see me today.
لقد جاءت الابنة الكبرى لعائلة لين لرؤيتي اليوم.
She said she's going to publish a report
قالت أنها ستنشر تقريرا
alleging that Dalun murdered her maid.
زاعمة أن دالون قتل خادمتها.
As you know,
كما تعلم،
our paper has the biggest circulation in Shanghai.
تتمتع صحيفتنا بأكبر توزيع في شنغهاي.
The Zeng family may be powerful,
قد تكون عائلة زينج قوية،
but the victim was only a maid.
ولكن الضحية لم تكن سوى خادمة.
If this gets published,
إذا تم نشر هذا،
it will cause such public outrage
سيؤدي ذلك إلى غضب شعبي كبير
and social pressure
والضغط الاجتماعي
that when you go to court,
أنه عندما تذهب إلى المحكمة،
hundreds of people will be outside, blocking the courthouse.
سيتجمع مئات الأشخاص بالخارج، مما سيؤدي إلى إغلاق قاعة المحكمة.
How could you possibly win that case?
كيف يمكنك الفوز بهذه القضية؟
It will influence the judge's decision.
وسوف يؤثر على قرار القاضي.
So tell me, should I publish it or not?
فأخبرني هل أنشره أم لا؟
You must not publish this.
لا يجوز لك نشر هذا.
Fine,
بخير،
I won't.
أنا لن.
But,
لكن،
putting our past as classmates aside,
وضع ماضينا كزملاء في الدراسة جانبًا،
based on my experience,
بناءً على تجربتي،
this piece would sell extremely well.
سيتم بيع هذه القطعة بشكل جيد للغاية.
If I don't publish this,
إذا لم أنشر هذا،
what am I supposed to tell
ماذا يفترض أن أقول؟
my editor-in-chief when he asks?
رئيس التحرير عندما يسألني؟
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Lu Yingchen,
لو ينجشن,
I'll buy every last copy of whatever you publish
سأشتري كل نسخة أخيرة من أي شيء تنشره
in tomorrow's paper.
في جريدة الغد.